MELONY ERIN FRANCHINI Backend Software Engineer

Colorado, USA • melony.franchini@gmail.com • +1.303.495.4624 • LinkedIn • GitHub

SUMMARY

Backend software engineer with an M.Ed. in Adult Learning and 7+ years as a professional educator. I bring a keen ability to learn new subject matter, break down complex concepts, and effectively communicate to diverse groups of people. My enthusiasm knows no bounds when tackling any level of complexity you throw my way!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Technology: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, SQL, PostgreSQL, Tailwind
- Testing: Test-Driven Development (TDD), CircleCI, Github Actions, Postman, RSpec
- Others: Agile Processes, GitHub, GitHub Projects, Heroku, SendGrid, Figma, Miro, HTML, CSS
- Exploring: Python, Django, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

ALPs (Advanced Language Practices), E2E Development Team | 60 hours | <u>BE Repo</u> & <u>FE Repo</u> Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, RSpec, GitHub, Postman, Github Actions, Heroku Created a web application to query AI with user input and return foreign language corrections.

- Wrote and refined OpenAl prompt query to return consistent and reliable responses.
- Led daily stand-up meetings which fostered cross-team collaboration and early project completion.
- Took on additional responsibilities that played a critical role in the successful delivery of the project.
- Researched 20+ hours: AWS Elastic Beanstalk deployment, EC2 instances, and DRS databases.

Do Good, Team Project | 50 Hours | <u>BE Repo</u> & <u>FE Repo</u>

Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, AWS S3 Bucket, Google Cloud, Twilio, Tailwind, CircleCI, Heroku Developed and deployed a web application using Service-Oriented Architecture & CRUD functionality.

- Initiated creation of a JSON contract to guarantee delivery of minimum viable product within tight deadline.
- Authenticated users with Google OAuth & rendered their Google Calendar with Google Cloud.
- Optimized database storage by storing and retrieving image metadata via an Amazon AWS S3 bucket.
- Collaborated via GitHub projects to ensure version control and facilitate efficient code reviews.

Whether the Weather, Solo Project | 40 Hours | Repo

Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Capybara, JSON, GitHub *Independently built a successful, backend web application.*

- Exposed a custom API that aggregates data consumed from multiple external endpoints.
- Implemented user password authentication, API key creation, and API key validation.
- Sharpened newly acquired knowledge, creative problem-solving skills, and decision-making abilities.

Mentoring Side Projects: Phoenix Mythical Creature (Ruby) | Potluck (Ruby) | Zoo Manager (MCV) Led workshops & mentoring sessions to reinforce fundamental skills with incoming cohorts of Turing students.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Apprentice: Backend Engineer | Turing School of Software & Design | Remote

11/2022 - 06/2023

Nearing the end of an ACCET-accredited, Ruby on Rails engineering program; completion set for mid-June.

University Lecturer | KEPCO International Nuclear Graduate School | South Korea

03/2016 - 03/2018

• Established first writing curriculum: Academic Writing, Thesis Writing, and Technical Presentations.

English Language Instructor | Korea Hydro & Nuclear Power Co. | South Korea

02/2014 - 03/2016

Developed a professional English training program to improve teaching skills of senior engineers.

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software and Design | Certificate of Completion
University of British Columbia | Master of Education (M.Ed.) in Adult Learning and Global Change
University of Nevada, Las Vegas | Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) in Theatre Arts

06/2023

05/2018 08/2006